<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>politics on Rahul Jha (~RJ722) Blog</title><link>https://rj722.github.io/red/tags/politics/</link><description>Recent content in politics on Rahul Jha (~RJ722) Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:28:48 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rj722.github.io/red/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Silk Road, Revolutions and Systems</title><link>https://rj722.github.io/red/blog/revolution-and-systems/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:28:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rj722.github.io/red/blog/revolution-and-systems/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, I read the &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/2015/04/silk-road-1/">story of Silk Road&lt;/a> about how a particular young
idealist Ross Ulbricht, tired of chasing success the old school way, found his
way around the darkweb&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> to create an online bazaar for the trading of illicit
materials, mainly drugs, which he named Silk Road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The aim behind writing this blog post is to think out loud and try to gain
insight into the oversights made by some of the most prominent revolutionaries
in history.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Freedom of Speech, Authoritarianism, Freedom of Press and Faiz</title><link>https://rj722.github.io/red/blog/freedom-of-speech/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:28:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rj722.github.io/red/blog/freedom-of-speech/</guid><description>Right to Free Speech is essential for a democracy. This blog post aims to shed some light on the recent authoritarian attempts made by hindutva-right-wing to curb free speech and how can we fight back.
&amp;ldquo;India&amp;rsquo;s Divider in chief&amp;rdquo; TIME magazine, in it&amp;rsquo;s May 20 edition, featured the Prime Minister of India, Mr. Narendra Damodardas Modi on it&amp;rsquo;s cover page
India&amp;#39;s Divider in Chief The article opens with the sentence:</description></item><item><title>A glimpse into the darkness: the 'Brutish' rule in India</title><link>https://rj722.github.io/red/blog/a-glimpse-into-the-darkness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:28:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rj722.github.io/red/blog/a-glimpse-into-the-darkness/</guid><description>A second-generation freeborn attempts to understand the impact and aftermath of colonization of India by British. It turns out that even an educated Indian of today is still not aware of the atrocities and turmoil it caused the country.
India - the golden bird of medieval times, known for it&amp;rsquo;s riches - the diamonds and the muslins, one of the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest exporter of silk - a country sharing a cut of more than 27% in the world&amp;rsquo;s economy during the sixteenth century - the country which was then capitalized for 200 years all the while feeding to the interests of Britain, leaving the post-British India with a crumbling share of a little more than 3% in the world GDP.</description></item></channel></rss>