<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on Rahul Jha (~RJ722) Blog</title><link>https://staging.rj722.tk/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on Rahul Jha (~RJ722) Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:28:48 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://staging.rj722.tk/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>"isn't a title of this post" isn't a title of this post</title><link>https://staging.rj722.tk/blog/self-referential-blog-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:28:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://staging.rj722.tk/blog/self-referential-blog-post/</guid><description>In the early part of the last century, when David Hilbert was working on stricter formalization of geometry than Euclid, Georg Cantor had worked out a theory of different types of infinities, the theory of sets. This theory would soon unveil a series of confusing paradoxes, leading to a crisis in the Mathematics community  regarding the stability of the foundational principles of the math of that time.
Central to these paradoxes was the Russell&amp;rsquo;s paradox (or more generally, as we&amp;rsquo;d talk about later, the Epimenides Paradox).</description></item><item><title>The [deceptive] power of visual explanation</title><link>https://staging.rj722.tk/blog/visual-explanation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:28:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://staging.rj722.tk/blog/visual-explanation/</guid><description>Quite recently, I came across Jay Alammar&amp;rsquo;s beautiful blog post, &amp;ldquo;A Visual Intro to NumPy &amp;amp; Data Representation&amp;rdquo;.
Before reading this, whenever I had to think about an array:
In [1]: import numpy as np In [2]: data = np.array([1, 2, 3]) In [3]: data Out[3]: array([1, 2, 3]) I used to create a mental picture somewhat like this:
┌────┬────┬────┐ data = │ 1 │ 2 │ 3 │ └────┴────┴────┘ But Jay, on the other hand, uses a vertical stack for representing the same array.</description></item><item><title>Using Weechat with Glowing Bear for IRC</title><link>https://staging.rj722.tk/blog/using-weechat-with-glowing-bear/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:28:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://staging.rj722.tk/blog/using-weechat-with-glowing-bear/</guid><description>Last month, I had a new addition to my toolbox - Glowing Bear, which has been a really nice improvement, allowing me to access Weechat (hosted on a server) through my browser. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I set it up.
But, before we begin - the curious folks might ask, &amp;ldquo;What had you been using all this time?&amp;rdquo;
Previously, I could directly ssh1 into my server, and attach to a screen session which ran weechat, using the command:</description></item></channel></rss>