<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Productivity on Rahul Jha (~RJ722) Blog</title><link>https://rj722.com/blog/tags/productivity/</link><description>Recent content in Productivity on Rahul Jha (~RJ722) Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 04:11:13 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rj722.com/blog/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Experience with OBM</title><link>https://rj722.com/blog/experience-with-obm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:28:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rj722.com/blog/experience-with-obm/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you want an overview about OBM, please &lt;a href="https://rj722.com/blog/obm/">read my post on the same&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve participated in three sprints until now, in which I&amp;rsquo;ve completely failed
myself, but I&amp;rsquo;ve already experiencing a drastic changes in my habits, which is
good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from this short, but significant experience:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First and foremost, the structure of OBM forces you to formalize things. You
need to setup goals for yourself. Even better is that the setup makes it very
difficult to be vague. You&amp;rsquo;ve to setup smaller tasks you need to achieve in
order to complete the goal. The research, which is required for listing these
tasks (thus, providing you with a big picture), getting a correct estimate of
time required, helps you plan efficiently.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Operation Blue Moon</title><link>https://rj722.com/blog/obm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:28:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rj722.com/blog/obm/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of years since I read &lt;a href="http://www.shakthimaan.com/what-to-do.html">&amp;ldquo;i want 2 do project tell me wat 2
do&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>, which then landed me on the home page of &lt;a href="https://gitlab.com/shakthimaan/operation-blue-moon/">Operation Blue Moon
(OBM)&lt;/a>, a project run single-handedly by the author of the book - &lt;a href="http://shakthimaan.com/">Shakthi
Kannan (mbuf)&lt;/a>. It is aimed towards time management and getting things
done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The project not only borrows it&amp;rsquo;s name, but also the spirit of discipline, from
our miliary counterparts. The practices here, built upon Shakthi&amp;rsquo;s years of
experience of dealing with people trying, and failing, and learning from their
mistakes, regarding time management.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>